We’re delighted you could join us.
Welcome to JW Broadcasting®
for December 2021!
The Watchtower Bible School of Gilead
has now completed 150 classes!
This certainly is a theocratic milestone
made possible with Jehovah’s help.
This 150th class was a little different.
There were only 24 students,
which is much less than usual.
And because of travel restrictions
based on the COVID-19 pandemic,
all are citizens of the United States.
Though this group
was different than in years past,
the goal remained the same:
to strengthen their faith
so that they can strengthen others
wherever they are assigned.
The graduation program helped the students
to focus on key points
they will benefit from on into the future.
Please enjoy Part 1 of the graduation
that was held
on Saturday, September 11, 2021,
at the Watchtower Educational Center
in Patterson, New York!
I’m going to go back many decades ago
—Monday, March 6, 1972.
Now, some of you in the class weren’t alive.
I think I know of one for sure who was alive.
That’s an inside joke, not Inside Story
—but anyway.
And along with my wife,
we had the privilege
(and that was rare
unless you were a Bethelite)
to attend the graduation
of the Watchtower Bible School of Gilead.
That was the 52nd class.
So we’re in the Assembly Hall
(jam packed there in New York City)
and just enjoying it.
What a privilege for us to sit there
and enjoy that program of the 52nd class!
Now here we are almost 100
(just two shy) classes later
—the 150th class.
And now we’re grateful
because many are tied in live as we speak.
But then the rest of the brotherhood
is going to have it available
in a few months.
So boy, things have changed,
and they enjoy that privilege.
But that was a rare privilege.
And I remember
Brother Knorr was the chairman
of the program.
And certainly, he just loved Gilead.
I mean, that you’ve got to give him.
Of course, Jehovah used him mightily
to get it all started there
—1943 was the first one.
But knowing that the beast was coming out,
Jehovah blessed them and said,
‘Yeah, we need a missionary school.’
There was a missionary school for years.
But anyway, the thing I wanted to mention
is that I remember an outstanding talk.
I had heard Brother Fred Franz
the summer before
at the Yankee Stadium convention,
but we were a little closer there
in the Assembly Hall.
And I’ll tell you what;
I was just glued to him.
If you had the privilege to hear him,
Jehovah blessed—
He had a blessed, beautiful mind.
He could just quote these scriptures.
And I’ve told folks:
“Now, if you don’t pay attention
and stay with him,
“you’re going to get lost.
He’s going to lose you.”
But if you paid attention,
it was thrilling
just to hear him pour out his heart
because it was all written
on his figurative heart.
But he discussed Ecclesiastes 5.
That’s why I was thinking
of bringing it up for your class here.
Because this is really directed to you.
And he spoke there about vows.
In those first seven verses,
dreams are mentioned.
And I appreciate it because it just struck me
when he mentioned it.
The dreams don’t refer to dreams
one has while they’re sleeping
because of the busy day.
Now, you can’t get that on your own
by just reading Ecclesiastes
with whatever version you have.
It had to do with getting sidetracked
with personal pursuits.
These dreams
—these are the things they’re doing.
And that would be “vanity”
(as we’d said then).
So let’s just take a moment
(you here in the class and others
who want to follow along in Ecclesiastes 5)
and just touch on some of the nice things.
And, of course, you could—
Now, don’t do it right now,
but you can do it later.
You have access to the Research Guide
—an in-depth understanding
of this wisdom in Ecclesiastes.
And Brother Franz addressed it.
For example, verse 1 says: “Watch your step.”
So this is for you soon-to-be graduates.
Jehovah is saying: “Watch your step.”
Don’t stop doing that.
You have thus far,
so continue to “watch your step.”
And he mentions those morally “stupid ones.”
That’s not you.
You can avoid that.
And then I love this in verse 2:
“Do not be quick with your mouth.”
Boy, there are a lot of people in the world
who could benefit from that counsel.
Isn’t that true?
It’s like:
‘Does he or she ever shut up?
‘I mean, they must—
I bet you they talk in their sleep.
They just won’t shut up.’
Then, anyway,
‘don’t be quick with your mouth,’
particularly in context here
when you’re speaking to Jehovah.
Boy, those are some good things
to keep in mind,
especially for you brothers
who will speak in public.
But you sisters too, when it’s personal
with your prayers to Jehovah,
don’t be quick with your mouth
when you approach
the Sovereign of the universe.
Your words should be few.
You do not impress God with vocabulary.
He’s impressed with sincerity of heart.
He loves those who love him.
And in all different languages,
he treasures those prayers.
And then he mentions this:
“A dream comes
from too many preoccupations.”
In the revised Bible here,
it says “too many cares.”
So this idea isn’t just dreams
from a busy, busy day.
This preoccupation with self
is being warned against here.
Don’t do it.
See, do not do it.
Don’t be preoccupied with yourself.
And for those who are,
there are many words from them.
But be careful, you know.
You have the privilege now;
you’ll be praying more in public
—probably more than you ever have before.
You get privileges, you know.
And when you’re praying to Jehovah,
sometimes—
We don’t want to be counseling
or criticizing prayers.
We try to be careful of that.
But sometimes you even hear
a prayer at Bethel, and it’s like:
‘OK. We’re trying to eat breakfast here.’
And I’ve told folks that it’s like,
you know, I just can’t help but—
Jesus is there, the most eloquent person
to walk the planet,
and the meal comes.
He ‘raised his eyes to heaven’
and “gave thanks.”
“Amen.
Let’s eat.”
I mean, there are other times
you want to pour out your heart and all that,
but you’re not praying to the audience.
You’re talking
to the Sovereign of the universe.
The counsel is, you know—
“Now I’m a Gilead graduate
(you brothers particularly),
so I’m going to have longer prayers.”
I hope not.
I sure hope not unless they’re private.
But then he gets into something crucial,
and it’s just so important
to keep in mind verse 4.
Let’s read verses 4 and 5:
“Whenever you make a vow to God,
“do not delay to pay it,
for he finds no pleasure
in the stupid ones [morally stupid].”
Then it’s very clear:
“What you vow, pay.”
And then:
“[It’s] better for you not to vow
than to vow and not pay.”
So this is serious counsel,
and the warning is,
Don’t allow your mouth to cause you to sin.
So when it comes to vows
(and some of you are married),
well, you have the vow.
You always have to hold on to that.
It’s not a light matter with Jehovah God.
And any other vows—be careful.
If you’re going to make a vow,
it’s between you and him.
But see, notice here:
“Do not allow [in verse 6]
your mouth to cause you to sin,
“and do not say before the angel
“[see, think about this]
that it was a mistake.”
So Jehovah has the angels
doing all sorts of things.
We don’t even begin to know the things
that are always going on all the time
with Jehovah’s servants and his holy angels.
It’s priceless.
But see, angels are, according to this,
assigned to check on these things.
So you don’t say to the angel:
“Why, look, I made a mistake.
Forgive me.”
Uh-uh.
You made a vow.
But see, it shouldn’t be
because an angel is going to check
that that’s Jehovah’s direction.
It should be
because of our love for Jehovah.
When you make a vow (you know,
whether it was marriage or whatever),
it’s your love for Jehovah
—that’s what cements the vow.
It matters.
See, it matters to him.
So then finally, in verse 7:
“For just as many preoccupations
lead to dreams,
so, too, many words lead to futility.”
So it’s good counsel.
You are so filled
with the Word of God.
This is a special class,
and Gilead is a special school.
We have other schools, SKE;
I’ll mention something later about that.
But this is unique
—to have men whom
Jehovah has appointed to instruct.
The Teaching Committee selects them
—totally whole-souled
and devoted to Jehovah God—
to teach you during the class.
And you’re going over all these things
in the Word of God.
And so it’s all in there,
and it’s just special.
So you thank Jehovah
that you have this education,
and you’re going
to move forward to glorify him.
And that’s pretty similar
to what is mentioned here
in the last sentence in verse 7:
“But fear the true God.”
So you soon-to-be graduates,
keep those words in your heart.
Just “fear the true God” in the days ahead,
and stay away from these kind of dreams
about self-preoccupation, you know?
Mm-mm.
No, not for you.
Otherwise, your education was futile,
not good.
And I don’t see that in any of you
(and I’m not implying).
But it’s such wise counsel
from Jehovah God in his Word.
So there’s much, much more there.
Enjoy thinking about it
with a little tool we have there,
the Research Guide.
Now, we appreciate the next speaker very much
(and he put his heart into his talk),
Brother Mark Sanderson.
And we have a nice lineup
of the brothers who’ve prepared their talks
with all their heart.
Mark is a member of the Governing Body,
and his talk is a question as a theme,
“What Will They Be Like?”
Brother Sanderson, please.
At Luke 6:40, Jesus said:
“A student is not above his teacher,
“but everyone who is perfectly instructed
will be like his teacher.”
Well, now, what comes to your mind
when you think about this verse?
Maybe you tend to think of it in terms
of when you conduct
a Bible study with someone.
Or you might think about it
when you go to a program like Gilead
and you’re instructed there.
But in reality,
we are all teachers every day
in the classroom of Christian living.
If we have responsibilities,
if we enjoy certain privileges,
our brothers and sisters will watch us.
And those who work closely with us
will learn from us.
And they will become like us.
Take the example of the apostle Paul.
Now, we know Paul
was an outstanding teacher.
Can you imagine?
Under inspiration,
he had the privilege to write 14 books
of the Christian Greek Scriptures.
Yet, that was not the only way
that the apostle Paul taught others.
His example in Christian living
was very powerful.
Now, what could people learn
from the example of Paul?
Let’s consider some examples.
Let’s go first to 1 Thessalonians chapter 2,
1 Thessalonians chapter 2,
and let’s look at verse 7:
“On the contrary,
we became gentle in your midst,
“as when a nursing mother
tenderly cares for her own children.
“So having tender affection for you,
“we were determined to impart to you,
“not only the good news of God
“but also our very selves,
because you became so beloved to us.”
Paul worked hard for the brothers.
He was kind.
He was gentle with them.
He was willing to give
not just the message of the truth but,
as he says in verse 8, “our very selves.”
And brothers, that was the truth.
Paul said he was willing to do “all things
for the sake of the good news.”
And just consider
some of the things that he did.
Let’s go to 2 Corinthians chapter 11
and just remind ourselves of some
of the things Paul went through.
Second Corinthians 11:23
—Paul says:
“Are they ministers of Christ?
“I reply like a madman,
I am more outstandingly one:
“I have done more work,
been imprisoned more often,
“suffered countless beatings,
and experienced many near-deaths.
“Five times I received
40 strokes less one from the Jews,
“three times I was beaten with rods,
“once I was stoned,
three times I experienced shipwreck,
a night and a day
I have spent in the open sea.”
And the list just goes on.
What could these ones
who worked with Paul learn from him?
In other words, how did
Paul’s powerful example
of love for God,
of endurance, of hard work,
and of true unselfishness
affect those around him?
Well, consider Timothy,
who worked so closely with Paul.
What did Paul say about him?
Let’s go to Philippians chapter 2
—Philippians 2:20.
Paul said: “For I have no one else
“of a disposition like his
“who will genuinely care for your concerns.
“For all the others
are seeking their own interests,
“not those of Jesus Christ.
“But you know the proof he gave of himself,
“that like a child with a father
he slaved with me
to advance the good news.”
Well, now, here’s a question:
Why was Timothy that way?
Why was Timothy so unselfish?
Why did he work so hard for other people?
Well, no doubt, he was “perfectly instructed”
not just by the words
but by the example of Paul.
Well, the same thing
could be true of Priscilla and Aquila.
Paul said about them
that they had risked their necks for him.
Well, where did they learn that from?
You see, we could go on
with other examples
of other close associates of Paul,
but what is the point?
Paul’s example in Christian living
instructed those around him.
They became like Paul.
Now, why is that important to you
who are graduating today
from the Watchtower Bible School of Gilead?
Well, very soon you’re going to be graduates,
and your mandate is to go forth
and strengthen and stabilize
the field and branch territory.
But now, that’s a big long term, isn’t it?
What is the field and branch territory?
It’s people.
It’s people
—spiritual men and women
who want to learn,
who want to be trained,
who want to reach the spiritual goals
that they’ve set for themselves,
and who want to grow to Christian maturity.
And because you are a Gilead graduate,
they will watch you, they will listen to you,
and they will be instructed by your example.
When I went to serve many years ago
where the need was great
on the island of Newfoundland,
we were so blessed
to have in our congregation
a graduate of the 7th class of Gilead,
Brother Fred Wiens.
Brother Wiens was an anointed brother
who was baptized
in 1928.
Now, I’ll be honest with you;
I don’t remember even one talk
that Fred Wiens gave.
But his warmth, his sense of humor,
his zeal for the ministry,
and his love for people
—the example that he set—
is truly unforgettable.
Fred talked to everyone
—and I mean everyone—
in the ministry.
One time we were out in service;
we pulled into the gas station.
As soon as we stopped the car,
Fred jumped out.
And when we were ready to leave,
we looked around to try to find Fred.
He wasn’t in the store;
he wasn’t in the bathroom.
He was nowhere to be seen.
Finally, we thought
we’d check the other cars.
Well, that’s exactly where Fred was.
Fred had knocked on the window
and gotten in a car
and started to preach
to all the people in that car.
Fred has now gone on to his reward.
But his example of warmth, kindness,
zeal, and love for people
continue to teach me
—and many others who knew him well—
right down to this day.
So here is the question
that rests before you:
What will you teach others by your example?
Be like Paul.
Love your brothers and sisters
right from your heart.
Through your example,
create an atmosphere of warmth and love
like a greenhouse
where young plants
can blossom and grow.
Your fine example
can warm up a congregation,
a circuit, a Bethel department,
perhaps even a branch office.
Never allow yourself
to be a cold executive
who creates an atmosphere like a freezer,
because those little plants
will shrivel up
and they will stop growing
in that environment.
Yes, be willing to impart
not just the many wonderful truths
of God’s Word that you learned at Gilead
but also your own heart and your own soul.
And then because those beautiful,
spiritual people you work with
will be properly instructed,
what will they be like?
They will be just like you.
And may the blessing
of our marvelous God, Jehovah,
go with you wherever you go.
Thank you very much, Brother Sanderson,
for that interesting Scriptural discussion
and some of those past experiences.
Of course, the brother might be saying,
‘You should have paid
closer attention to my talks.’
No, no.
It was obvious how much you loved him.
So, OK.
Clive Martin,
a helper to the Writing Committee,
is going to address us now
with this interesting theme,
“Remember the Terms of Peace?”
Have you ever had to sue for peace?
While you’re thinking of that question,
would you please turn with me
to Luke chapter 14?
I’d like to put you and me
in the middle of one of Jesus’ illustrations.
Jesus has been talking about what it costs
to become one of his disciples.
And then in verse 31, he says:
“Or what king
“[this is where we come in, what king]
“marching out against another king in war
“does not first sit down and take counsel
whether he is able with 10,000 troops
“to stand up to the one who comes
against him with 20,000?
“If, in fact, he cannot do so,
“then while that one is yet far away,
he sends out a body of ambassadors
and sues for peace.”
How do you think that conversation goes?
“I want peace, and these are my terms.”
Hardly!
It’s more like:
“I don’t want to be your enemy.
Please tell me what to do
so that I can have peace with you.”
Now, with that in mind,
Jesus gives the application, verse 33:
“In the same way, you may be sure
that not one of you
“who does not say good-bye
to all his belongings
can be my disciple.”
That is you and me.
We got to the point where we realized
we did not want to be an enemy of Jehovah.
And so we were willing
to sacrifice everything
—belongings, career, status, everything—
for the privilege of being
at peace with Jehovah
and being a disciple of his Son.
Now for you students of class 150,
your pursuit of peace with Jehovah
has led you
into the special full-time service.
And what a beautiful record
every one of you has set!
You remind me in many ways
of a group in the Bible
that literally sued for peace.
Their story is told
in the book of Joshua chapter 9.
That’s right;
we’re talking about the Gibeonites.
Do you have Joshua chapter 9?
Now, they had heard of all the things
that Jehovah had done
for his people, Israel, and to his enemies.
They did not want to be Jehovah’s enemy.
And so they did exactly
what the king in Jesus’ illustration did.
They sent a body of ambassadors.
So Joshua chapter 9
—and this is the opening overture
in verse 6:
“We have come from a distant land.
Now make a covenant with us.”
When they didn’t get a very warm
initial reception, they persisted.
Verse 8: “We are your servants.”
In other words,
“Set the terms; we want peace.”
They were willing to sacrifice everything
in order to enjoy peace
with Israel and with Israel’s God.
Now, Joshua and the chieftains
didn’t see it exactly the same way,
particularly when they found out
that they were not from a distant land
as they had claimed.
Nobody likes to be fooled.
So the tone got a little sterner.
So turn and look at verse 23.
This is what they said:
“From now on you are cursed,
“and you will always occupy
a slave’s position
as gatherers of wood and drawers of water
for the house of my God.”
What will the Gibeonites say to that?
Verse 25: “We are at your mercy.
Do to us whatever you think
is good and right.”
And just so, the terms of peace were set.
Verse 27: “That day Joshua made them
“gatherers of wood and drawers of water
“for the assembly and for Jehovah’s altar
“at the place that He should choose,
and they remain so to this day.”
So now a few questions, a few lessons.
What do you think
of the Gibeonites’ assignment?
It was presented to them as a punishment.
But just think,
they weren’t being sold off
as household slaves.
Their humble service
would directly contribute
to pure worship and support Jehovah’s people.
That’s a privilege, isn’t it?
That’s the kind of service
we reach out for as a privilege.
Now, the kind of service—
Was it because they were lowly people,
no skills to do anything else,
that they were given this kind of job?
Well, look at chapter 10
and verse 2
and see the kind of people
the Gibeonites were:
“Gibeon was a great city,
like one of the royal cities.
“It was greater than Ai,
and all its men were warriors
[capable, skilled people].”
However,
clearly the Gibeonites realized
that if their army was no match for Israel,
then Jehovah didn’t need them
to bolster his army
in order to complete the conquest.
It was better for them
to ask Jehovah what he wanted them to do
and to do that.
So the sacrifice was definitely worth it.
Does that mean, though,
that their skills were irrelevant,
never even considered?
Well, no.
For example, a few hundred years later,
Ishmaiah the Gibeonite
is listed among David’s 30 mighty men.
Different needs call for different skills.
What did Ishmaiah do with his skill?
Well, he humbly defended pure worship
and Jehovah’s people.
So the details of the assignment
were different,
but the focus was about the same.
Another question: Was this just
a short-term starter assignment?
“Yes, we will do this for now,
but once the campaign is over,
we’ll be able to resume
our regular place in society.”
Go back to verse 27 of chapter 9.
Remember what Joshua said at this point
when he gave them their assignment?
“They remain so to this day.”
Not only to the day
that Joshua wrote these words
but about 900 years later
among the exiles that returned
from Babylon to Jerusalem
to restore pure worship
there were temple servants,
and likely
this included descendants of the Gibeonites.
Just think, these temple servants
once again were willing to leave behind
the life that they’d built up
to make the trek in behalf of pure worship
and take up their duties.
They must have really cherished
their assignment
in order to stick to it that way.
So as we’ve talked about them,
have you been noting some personal lessons?
These are the four that come to my mind.
Number one, as with the king
in Jesus’ illustration and the Gibeonites,
peace with Jehovah is such a treasure.
We’re willing to sacrifice
anything to enjoy it.
Number two, Jehovah’s terms for us
include humble service
on behalf of pure worship
and in support of his people,
and that kind of humble service
we view as the greatest privilege.
Number three, different needs
call for different skills,
and that may lead to a change of assignment
for you or for someone else.
Either way, we don’t compete
and we don’t compare.
The details of the assignment
may be different,
but the focus, or goal, is always the same.
And the fourth one,
we cherish our assignments.
We’re going to stay in them
as long as Jehovah allows.
In short, we cherish our assignments;
we love our God.
Peace with Jehovah is a treasure
that we will never let go.
Thank you very much.
We appreciated that very much.
We’re now at peace, Brother Martin.
Thank you
for those kind, encouraging thoughts.
Now, this is something special
for you here in the class,
the 150th class of Gilead.
Now, you may be wondering
about your post-graduation life.
You’ve probably been doing that
at least a couple of weeks.
And how will you use
what you’ve learned from Gilead
to strengthen and stabilize
the branch organization and others?
And Brother Sanderson touched on that,
and you’ll hear more later about that.
That’s our purpose.
Now, here’s a question to ponder.
What if you could look down the road
—let’s say 2, 4, 6,
or even 30 years
into the future from this day of graduation?
It’d be nice to be able to do.
Well, we’re pleased to inform you
that the Teaching Committee has included
at this graduation a special feature
in connection with this graduation.
It consists of four prerecorded interviews
of Gilead graduates
currently in their assignments.
And all four of the brothers
are serving on Branch Committees;
they’re Branch Committee members.
So the interviews will begin now,
and then another will follow
each of the next three parts of the program.
So we’ll have a part and then an interview.
Now, first,
we’re going to travel to the country
of the Democratic Republic of Congo.
There we find a brother who graduated
from the 138th class of Gilead.
Listen as he explains how his Gilead training
has helped him to work humbly
with his fellow brothers
and Branch Committee members.
Enjoy the video.
Brother and Sister Kabitshwa
will be returning to Congo.
It’s difficult
to find one word,
or expression,
that can sum up what I personally feel
after this training in Gilead.
The in-depth study of Jehovah’s personality
opened my eyes more fully
to the way he values people.
And this has helped me to look
for opportunities to strengthen others
by placing their interests above my own.
For example, my wife and I
made ourselves available
to support the brothers
in cleaning a regional convention venue.
They laughed, thinking that we were joking.
And finally, they gave us
humble tasks in cleaning.
We did it with joy, and it allowed me
to get to know the brothers
in the circuits better.
Taking these opportunities
has a much more profound effect
on the brothers
than simply giving talks.
Gilead has also helped me
to show honor to the other members
of the Branch Committee.
On the committee I serve,
there are brothers of different age groups.
While I feel that my normal inclination
is to speak too much,
I have learned from others on the committee
how to humbly listen.
For example, I had to present a concept
to the Branch Committee,
and I put all my heart into the presentation.
I was 100 percent sure it would be approved.
Guess what?
None of the options were approved.
Honestly, inside myself,
I was upset and ready to give up.
What helped me was meditating on the example
of another fellow Branch Committee member
and how he reacted in times like this.
Thanks to Gilead, I have learned
to benefit from the qualities
of each one of the brothers I work with,
no matter who they are
or the experience they have.
Jehovah’s organization
is made up of people
from different cultures and backgrounds,
and these differences can at times be to us
like a huge gap that threatens our unity.
In one of our lessons at Gilead,
Matthew 5:3 was used to show
that the only way to bridge the gap
is to be a spiritual person.
So every time I’m overwhelmed
by a feeling of inadequacy
or I’m about to vent my frustrations,
I reconnect to Jehovah and Jesus
by studying the Bible and praying for help.
I would definitely say that Gilead
has given me all the tools I need
to build the bridge of unity
among Jehovah’s people whenever I see a gap
—and that tool is
to feed my own spirituality.
That was a nice addition for the program.
We look forward to the other videos.
Now, next,
we have a helper to the Teaching Committee.
He’s been so for a long time.
I’m not picking on your age, Bill,
but you look good.
That’s because his wife, Sandy,
is right out there,
so I try to be careful.
Now, we always look forward
to what Brother Malenfant has
to share with us.
His theme is “‘Boast in Jehovah.’”
There are many people who love to boast.
Politicians frequently boast
about what they have done
and what they have promised to do
for their constituents.
And businessmen,
they love to boast
about how successful they are
and how much money they are making.
And athletes, you know,
athletes are prideful, many of them.
And they boast about the events
that they’ve been great in
and that they’ve won.
In fact, you know, it’s interesting to note
that in the highly competitive sports world,
there is an expression for great achievers.
The expression is GOAT
—G-O-A-T—
greatest of all time.
Can you imagine people thinking
that somehow they have been
the greatest of all time?
When we hear the words
“greatest of all time,”
only one person comes to mind.
He was the greatest man who ever lived
—truly the greatest of all time,
Jesus Christ.
And his greatness had nothing to do
with politics, business,
or playing games.
But it had everything to do
with praising Jehovah and boasting
in Jehovah God.
Jesus knew the counsel that’s recorded
at Jeremiah chapter 9,
verses 23, 24.
And this scripture, this text, is beautiful.
Jeremiah 9:23, 24
—it says:
“This is what Jehovah says:
“‘Let not the wise man boast
about his wisdom;
“‘let not the mighty man boast
about his mightiness;
“‘and let not the rich man boast
about his riches.
“‘But let the one boasting
“‘boast about this:
“‘That he has insight and knowledge of me,
“‘that I am Jehovah,
“‘the One showing loyal love,
“‘justice, and righteousness in the earth,
“‘for in these things
I take delight,’ declares Jehovah.”
Isn’t that beautiful?
So to boast in Jehovah really means
that we take pride in our God, Jehovah.
We’re proud to bear his name.
We rejoice in his reputation.
We’ve got it in the Scriptures,
and we can see it
in the organization today.
And Jehovah takes delight
when we boast in him
—in his provisions, in his justice,
in his promises, and in his loyal love.
So you students of the 150th class of Gilead
(students, soon-to-be graduates,
I should add),
you’ve got a lot of reasons
to boast in Jehovah God.
And you know that throughout his ministry,
Jesus boasted in Jehovah.
If you examine closely the Scriptures
and things that Jesus said,
you’ll be able to see on many occasions
how he boasted in Jehovah.
Just to give you one example,
remember when the rich young ruler
approached Jesus and he said:
“[Oh,] Good Teacher”
to the Lord Jesus Christ?
And what did Jesus say?
“Why do you call me good?
Nobody is good except one, God.”
That was a wonderful boast
in Jehovah God, glorifying him.
So you students can boast in Jehovah
(you’ve been doing it for a long time)
because now you have
the privilege of going out,
fulfilling an assignment,
and showing how much
you really do rely on Jehovah God.
You can boast because you’ve experienced
what Jesus declared
at John 8:32.
Jesus said: “And you will know the truth,
and the truth will set you free.”
Well, that’s something we all know.
But don’t minimize it.
Appreciate the freedom you have right now
because you know the truth.
You’ve been set free
from the lies of this world
that hold people in bondage
about false beliefs in life and death.
You’re free from human thinking that man
is going to remedy
the problems of this old world,
and we know they can’t do it.
They haven’t got the wherewithal to do it.
No man can really “direct his [own steps],”
not even a perfect man.
Jehovah can deliver his people too.
Even where we’re under severe persecution,
Jehovah can intervene
whenever he sees fit to do so.
You can boast also in another thing
—that you are slaves of Jehovah.
Now, you’re in a unique position
because very few slaves
are allowed to choose their master,
but you’ve done it.
You’ve chosen Jehovah God
to be your Master and to be a slave to him.
And you know that Jehovah is with you.
And you’re happy, and you’re willing slaves
of Jehovah and of Jesus Christ.
And it’s a remarkable slavery, really,
because no one has the freedom
that we enjoy in our slavery to Jehovah God.
We’re so free and able to do so many things
serving Jehovah but all the while
enjoying the good life
that God has given to us.
You can boast also in the brotherhood,
that you can gather together
in assemblies to praise Jehovah God.
And you know Jesus’ words are true:
‘Two or three are gathered in his name.
There he is in our midst.’
So whether it’s tens of thousands
gathered together at a big convention
or two or three gathering together secretly,
you know that Jesus Christ is there with you.
You can also boast in the great privilege
you have through prayer.
Just think about it for a moment.
You can talk to the almighty Creator
of the universe personally.
That is really something quite remarkable.
But that is a privilege we have,
and we boast in the privilege we have
of addressing Jehovah
and asking him for his help,
for his spirit to guide us,
for his strength and protection.
And there’s something else too
that I find fascinating
that you can boast in.
You can boast because you bear
the fear-inspiring name
Jehovah’s Witnesses.
Think about that.
You’re carrying Jehovah’s name.
And how grateful, really,
we are that back in 1931
the visible part of Jehovah’s organization
adopted the name Jehovah’s Witnesses!
And it’s not just the name of a religion.
It’s a description of what people do.
They live their lives to honor Jehovah God.
They are living Witnesses of the Creator.
That is a privilege that we have,
and that separates us
from all religion on the earth.
And there’s no other religion
that wants that name anyhow.
But we’re delighted that we have it.
And they regret, perhaps a few,
that they didn’t listen to or adopt it.
We are God’s name people,
and at 1 Chronicles 16:10,
it says this: “Boast about his holy name.
Let the hearts of those
seeking Jehovah rejoice.”
And if you examine synonyms,
“rejoice” is a synonym in certain cases
for “boast”—to boast in Jehovah.
And you can boast over the fact that Jehovah
has allowed you a very special privilege.
You can see the unseen.
Not all people can do that.
The vision of many people in this world
is limited to just the physical
that they see before them,
but they can’t see the unseen.
I remember a man who said,
“What has God ever done for me?”
That poor man.
He was blind—totally blind spiritually.
He enjoyed food, drink,
the things the earth provides,
but he couldn’t see
behind those physical things.
He couldn’t see
that there had to be a wonderful Creator
who provided all of these things for him.
You can see the unseen.
You see Jesus Christ ruling
as King in the heavens.
You see the new world that’s coming.
You see the resurrection of the dead.
You see the functioning
of Jehovah God’s holy spirit
on his people today.
Finally, you know very well
that we’ve only touched
on a few things that you can boast in,
but you’ll want to continue doing that
—boasting in Jehovah.
And right now, I know
(all of you students) you feel great.
You’ve completed your course.
You’ve done it.
You’re graduating from Gilead School,
and now the doors of future activity
are swinging open to you.
So as you undertake your assignments,
whatever and wherever they may be,
do these things, please:
Stay humble,
be happy,
and work hard.
And always esteem highly
the great honor and privilege you have
to “boast in Jehovah.”
Thanks.
Thanks, Bill.
As usual, we thoroughly enjoyed your talk.
Now, our second prerecorded interview
of a Gilead graduate now in his assignment
takes us to Ecuador, South America.
This brother serves
on the Branch Committee in Ecuador,
and he graduated
from the 142nd class of Gilead.
Notice as he explains
(notice) the positive impact
that Gilead graduates had on him
from his childhood
and how his training while at Gilead
helped him to appreciate
what is truly important.
Brother and Sister Tapia
will be going back to Ecuador.
Gilead training is a beautiful way
that Jehovah is using divine education
to train people
—not only for their benefit.
By having Gilead graduates
all around the world,
we are sharing the impact of this school
on the brothers and sisters who are working
with these students and future graduates.
It was Gilead missionaries
who first introduced the truth to my parents
and helped them to the point of baptism.
So I have very pleasant memories
of Gilead graduates
being around my home since childhood.
The greatest legacy
I received through my Gilead training
is the privilege of getting to know
Jehovah’s beautiful personality more deeply.
I have been studying
the Bible since childhood,
but doing so with the help
of the Gilead instructors
really helped me to make connections
that I had never put together before.
You don’t go to Gilead to learn abilities,
which can sometimes overshadow
spiritual qualities.
Instead, a very important part
of Gilead training
is the study of Christ’s personality.
And you know, Jesus is mostly remembered
not so much for his abilities
but for how he perfectly reflected
the beautiful qualities of his father.
By getting to know Jehovah and Jesus better,
I was able to better see
where I need to improve.
Of course, it can be discouraging at times
to not always act as they do,
but that has helped me
to have the proper perspective
and to rely on Jehovah,
begging him for his guidance
while waiting for his help.
One of the best lessons
I took away from Gilead is
that people are more important
than tasks or deadlines.
People are the reason for our assignment,
and that is why I need to show my love
to my brothers and sisters.
Honestly, I don’t feel at all qualified
for this assignment,
but I have learned
that if Jehovah assigns us a certain task,
for sure he will give us
what we need to accomplish it.
That was very nice.
We certainly appreciate it.
Now, we have one
of the Gilead instructors next,
Brother James Cauthon.
And he’s chosen as his subject
“Thriving in the Trenches.”
Located in the western Pacific Ocean,
the Mariana Trench
is the deepest known location on earth.
To help you get an idea of its depth,
imagine that you could stack
the Empire State Building
in the trench.
It would take 25 such buildings to go
from the bottom of the trench
before you would reach sea level.
It is also one of the deadliest places
on earth.
Why is that?
In a word—pressure.
The crushing pressure, water pressure,
on the floor of the trench
is more than eight tons per square inch.
Now, to give you some idea,
that would be the equivalent
of having about 50 jumbo jets
on top of you.
Surely no life could live in that trench.
At least that’s what scientists thought.
But they were wrong.
When they finally developed a submersible
that would take them down into the trench,
they found life teeming
—and not just surviving but thriving.
Now, how is that possible?
It’s possible, friends,
because Jehovah, our Creator,
knows how to deal with pressure.
Jehovah knows how to deal with pressure.
And this is a fact
that should be comforting to all of us.
Why?
Because the pressure
in this system of things is increasing
—strain, stress, anxiety—
for all people at all levels.
And the Bible tells us
that these pressures are likely
to increase in the near future.
But the good news is
that Jehovah does more than
just equip his servants to survive.
He can actually make one thrive.
Here’s an example.
Try this on for pressure.
You’re surrounded by men who hate you.
In addition to hunting you down
with a view to taking your life,
they’ve spread slander and lies
about you everywhere.
Your name has become a reproach.
When people see you coming,
they turn and run the other way
because they feel that your time is short
and they don’t want to be caught
in the crosshairs.
Wherever you look,
it seems like terror is waiting for you.
And as a result of these problems,
you’re struggling with depression.
Your own sins are staring you in the face.
The whole experience
has taken a toll on your health.
You can’t sleep.
Your stamina is shot.
Your body is wasting away.
Now, that was David’s situation,
and you can read about it at Psalm 31:10-13.
The pressure was real
—no question about it.
David’s feelings were real
—no question about that.
But something else was very real.
And that was Jehovah.
And so Jehovah
was where David would turn to.
Let’s turn to his words in Psalm 31.
Psalm 31—and note his humble prayer
beginning in verse 14.
He said: “But I trust in you, O Jehovah,
“I declare: ‘You are my God.’
“My days are in your hand.
“Rescue me from the hand of my enemies
and from those persecuting me.
“Make your face shine upon your servant.
Save me by your loyal love.”
David’s life experiences
had taught him the value of turning to God
and pouring out his heart in times of trial.
And he absolutely knew that prayer,
coupled with implicit trust and patience,
would always bring Jehovah’s blessing.
And you see, friends,
the key to not just surviving
but thriving under extreme pressure
is to have the internal pressure
equal to the external.
And when this is true,
there is no amount of pressure
that can crush you.
So in a spiritual sense,
David received the internal fortitude
or, as some say,
“the intestinal fortitude,”
meaning “the courage and the strength
that would make him equal
to the pressure weighing in on him.”
And how do we know that he received that?
Well, let’s go back to Psalm 31
for just a moment.
If you look in verse 21, notice now
the change.
He says: “May Jehovah be praised,
“for in a wonderful way,
he has shown his loyal love to me
in a besieged city.”
And then in verse 23:
“Love Jehovah, all you who are loyal to him!
Jehovah protects the faithful.”
And finally in verse 24:
“Be courageous, and may your heart be strong,
all you who are waiting for Jehovah.”
So, you see, David
received an answer to his prayer
—his prayer coupled with his faith
and his patience.
He was waiting on Jehovah.
And Jehovah helped him not only to survive
but to thrive.
And he added joy to David
because David went on
to find joy and happiness
in his responsibilities and privileges.
So, what do we learn?
(1) David was able to face the pressure
because he had
an unshakable faith in Jehovah,
(2) David’s relationship with Jehovah
brought him the patience to wait on God,
and (3) when a loyal servant of God
humbly turns to Jehovah for help,
it is Jehovah’s own loyal love
that has the effect
of equalizing the pressure.
And, you know, there’s something else.
David’s experience in the trench
reached further than he ever knew.
Jonah, while in the belly of the great fish,
cited words from Psalm 31.
Jeremiah, who had
many trialsome times in his life,
often echoed phrases from Psalm 31.
And Jesus Christ himself,
the very Son of God—
His final words from the stake
were a quotation from Psalm 31:5.
So Jesus must have meditated
on this many times.
And so, friends, like David, Jonah, Jeremiah,
Jesus, and many, many others
—they all trusted in Jehovah,
and Jehovah never failed
to make them equal to the pressure.
He’ll do the same for you.
And so in conclusion,
you see, it really doesn’t matter
how great the pressure is.
It only matters where the pressure lies.
Do not let it come between you
and Jehovah
and your worship and service.
Don’t let it come between you,
because then the external pressure
will only continue to move you closer
to your heavenly Father.
The life that flourishes
in the Mariana Trench gives
a positive example, a beautiful example,
of Jehovah’s limitless ability
to help his creation
deal with pressure.
Prayer, trust, and patience
will always be rewarded by Jehovah.
Relief will come.
So remain close to your heavenly Father,
and you will not just survive
the pressure in the trench
but you will thrive spiritually.
Thank you, Brother Cauthon,
for your nice, insightful comments
—much appreciated.
Now, our third interview involves a brother
who serves as a member
of the Branch Committee
in Sri Lanka.
He graduated from the 146th class of Gilead
—so just four classes back.
Listen carefully as he explains
how Gilead training helped him
to see things about his personality
that he needed to refine
to become a stabilizing
and strengthening influence
in his branch territory.
Brother and Sister Sivakumaran
will be returning to Sri Lanka.
In Gilead, the wonderful thing
is that you get to learn
from the beginning
Jehovah’s dealings with humankind,
that vast history.
Learning that is humbling.
How tiny I am
and the small role that I play
in Jehovah’s organization are a realization!
Before going to Gilead,
I thought I was a loving person,
because we always think
we want to be loving people.
But during Gilead,
it was made aware to me
that I had a spiritual blind spot.
There were brothers and sisters
that I didn’t really notice before,
and that kind of taught me
an important lesson.
It’s not about giving talks,
but really it’s personal attention
that brothers need.
So I need to give them my time,
and I need to help them understand
that Jehovah loves them very much.
You know, one word that stands out
throughout the training is “mercy.”
Israel made many mistakes,
but Jehovah never picked on them
for their mistakes.
He just wanted them to come back to him,
and that was a lovely lesson.
As an overseer,
I need to ask a question that always,
you know, rings in my my ear,
‘Am I going to criticize,
or am I going to commend?’
Just to give you an example,
before going to Gilead,
as a home overseer
I was strict
and came across stingy,
to be honest.
But during Gilead,
it was made well aware to me
that I need to change.
I need to be more generous,
and I need to be merciful.
I vividly remember that one instructor said:
“Saying no to everything can be addictive,
and it makes for an easy way out.”
But we were admonished
to say yes whenever we can
and to help the brothers.
Summing up Gilead,
I can’t do better than Jesus.
Love Jehovah; love people
—that’s the whole training of Gilead.
And some of my feelings
every time I think about Gilead
are that I have a long way to go
to put all those details into practice
and to change myself to fit Jehovah.
So, yeah, I have a long way to go,
so I’m working on it.
So we pray that all
of you soon-to-be graduates
examine yourself to ensure
that you’ll have a strengthening effect
on the brotherhood.
It was nice, the humble expressions
he shared with us.
Now let’s turn our attention
to another one of the Gilead instructors
and a helper to the Teaching Committee,
Mark Noumair.
The title of his talk is
“‘I Cling to You; You Hold on to Me.’”
Brother Noumair.
In this talk, we want you to understand
the sustaining power of loyal love.
Because it is this quality, loyal love,
and its power
that will help you face future trials
and challenges with confidence in Jehovah.
Well, you perhaps remember the definition
of loyal love from a written review.
But it’s this: It is love motivated
by a strong commitment and a deep attachment.
And here’s how King David described
the loyal love that existed
between him and Jehovah.
He said at Psalm 63:8:
“I cling to you;
your right hand keeps fast hold on me.”
Now, this is loyal love,
‘I cling to you.
You hold on to me.’
Now, in the first century
—a woman—
a woman who set an outstanding example
of clinging to Jehovah is Anna.
How so?
Let’s find out.
We open our Bibles to Luke chapter 2.
We’re going to read verses 36 and 37
and see what lesson
we can learn and apply to you:
“Now there was a prophetess,
“Anna the daughter
of Phanuel, of Asher’s tribe.
“This woman was well along in years
“and had lived with her husband
for seven years after they were married,
“and she was a widow now 84 years old.
“She was never missing from the temple,
“rendering sacred service night and day
with fasting and supplications.”
Well, here we have it.
Everything we know about Anna is right here.
Luke recorded it.
She was 84 years old
when Luke introduces her to us.
Likely, she hadn’t lived long enough
to become a follower of Jesus,
to be anointed with holy spirit,
or to enjoy preaching
the good news of the Kingdom.
That’s it.
If  we stop right there.
But what if we don’t?
What if we dig deeper?
What will we learn that will help you?
Well, let’s do that.
Anna was born about 86 B.C.E.
When she was 23 years old,
Jerusalem was filled
with violence and divisions.
Jewish leaders
such as the Maccabees are at war.
Roman forces under the leadership
of a soldier named Pompey
came to restore order, and in the process,
some 12,000 Jews reportedly died.
It is possible that Anna’s husband
was one of these victims.
Then when Anna was 47 years old,
the Romans appointed Herod as king of Judea.
Herod?
This man was not a descendant of David.
He was not even an Israelite.
He was an Edomite.
The Edomites
were sworn enemies of true worship.
Now, on top of that,
the hypocritical Jewish religious leaders
made life hard for people,
including widows like Anna.
So now Anna watches
as Jehovah’s “house of prayer,”
the place she cherished,
became “a cave of robbers.”
Pure worship is withering on the vine.
What will Anna do?
She could have been stumbled.
She could have reasoned:
‘I supported true worship all my life.
‘I believed the Messiah would come
and the prophecies would come.
‘I go to the temple every day.
‘I’ve done everything right,
but things have only gotten worse.
‘God let my husband die;
an Edomite is rebuilding the temple.
‘What’s happening?
‘Has Jehovah left us?
Should I leave too?’
Anna could have given up,
walked away, became bitter.
But she didn’t.
Why? Why?
It was the roots of her loyal love,
that sustaining power of loyal love.
It went deep, and it wrapped around Jehovah.
And she had the power to keep clinging to him
under those circumstances.
Anna was determined to serve Jehovah
to the best of her ability.
What did she do?
Again, looking at verse 37:
“She was never missing from the temple,
“[She was in the right place.]
“rendering sacred service night and day
“[doing the right thing]
“with fasting and supplications
[with the right attitude].”
She was doing the right thing
in the right place with the right attitude.
Nothing could stop
this seemingly fragile servant of God
from clinging to her closest Friend, Jehovah.
In effect, Anna was saying,
“I cling to you, Jehovah.”
And her loyal love was noticed.
Chapter 2 and verse 38
reveals that Anna was present
when the baby Jesus
was brought to the temple.
And when she saw that baby,
what did she begin to do in verse 38?
It says: “She came near
and [she] began giving thanks to God
“and speaking about the child
to all who were waiting
for Jerusalem’s deliverance.”
Can you sense her joy?
Can you feel the joy she had
at seeing and, perhaps, even holding
that little baby, the future Messiah?
This was something that this elderly woman
had never expected in her lifetime.
The child in front of her was proof
—tangible proof, concrete evidence—
that Jehovah had not abandoned his people.
And he did not abandon Anna.
So not only had Anna clung to Jehovah
but Jehovah held on to her and
—and  rewarded her.
This is loyal love.
Anna’s faithful record
is so well-known
that some 50 years later,
50 years later or so,
Luke was compelled to write about her.
Where did he get his information?
Who did he talk to?
Did he talk to Mary or interview her
or some of the older ones?
‘There was this woman, Anna.
She was at the temple.
She would never leave.’
We don’t know.
But what we do know is
that Jehovah inspired Luke
to record and to document
her life in His Word
so that we could be taught lessons.
And here we are some 2,000 years later,
and we are using her life as an example
of commitment and unbreakable integrity
for you students to imitate.
So, what can you learn from Anna’s example?
You may suffer loss of one kind or another.
You will come face-to-face
with the imperfections of others.
Your feelings may get hurt,
you might find yourself coping
with an unexpected change
in your life that is not pleasant,
or you may feel that you’re a victim
of an injustice or a serious misunderstanding
from within the organization.
What will you do?
This is what you will do.
You will cling to Jehovah,
and you will experience him
holding on to you.
You cling to him.
He holds on to you.
For example,
I recall a time when a brother
serving in a foreign field
because of a misunderstanding
lost his privileges as an elder.
And he felt the decision was unfair.
He was deeply hurt.
But his wife— He and his wife
never stopped clinging to Jehovah
and their spiritual routine.
Then at a regional convention,
a brother approached him
and thanked him for the talk
that he gave on the program.
Well, he volunteered
in the cleaning department,
but he hadn’t given a talk.
Then the brother
now said to this former elder:
“When I see your smile and positive attitude,
“yes, you gave a talk.
“And it was on loyalty,
and it was loud and clear.”
So the former elder now relates this:
“The experience taught me and my wife
“that every challenge or misfortune
“does not need to represent a threat
“to our spiritual well-being.
“We’ve come to view rejection, failure,
“or being misunderstood as normal episodes
“in the lives of competent, healthy people.
Instead of being crushed, we grew.”
You see, the couple looked
beyond their hardships,
and they clung to Jehovah.
How?
By imitating Anna.
They were ‘never missing from true worship
‘[in the right place],
‘rendering sacred service day and night
‘[doing the right thing]
with fasting and supplications.’
And sometimes
those supplications involve tears
but with the right attitude.
And Jehovah held on to them and never let go.
The brother is still serving
in the foreign field.
He is an elder again
and giving memorable talks.
So, what do we want you
to remember from this talk?
We want you to remember this:
When you come face-to-face with future trials
(and you will)
or challenges in your life
(and you will, this is what happens in life),
be in the right place,
do the right thing
with the right attitude.
By doing this, you declare:
“Jehovah, I cling to you,
and I trust you to hold on to me.”
Thank you very much, Brother Noumair.
Anna is a beautiful example
for all of us.
No doubt about it.
Now, our final prerecorded interview takes us
to the West African country of Ghana,
where David and Lynne Jones
currently serve.
Upon their graduation from the 95th class
in September of 1993,
they were assigned
to the country of Kenya, East Africa.
They also served in Burundi for eight years.
Presently, they serve in Ghana,
where Brother Jones serves
as a member of the Branch Committee there.
Now, you might remember this couple
when you see the video
because their class was highlighted
in the video To the Ends of the Earth,
which marked the 50th anniversary
of the Watchtower Bible School of Gilead.
It was a very enlightening video for sure.
Although the purpose
of Gilead School training
has changed since then,
it’s clear from their heartfelt comments
that they’ve proven to be
a stabilizing and strengthening influence
where they have served.
So enjoy the video.
This is the day when we hand out assignments
to all of these students.
The morning that we knew
we were going to get our assignment,
we went down to morning worship,
and then we had to line up,
and we were waiting to get our assignment.
And my stomach was churning,
and I felt really sick
—sick with excitement
as well as the fact that you knew
that whatever Brother Jaracz said,
the next sentence that came out of his mouth
would determine the rest of your life.
It’s hard to imagine
that 28 years have gone by
since our initial assignment.
But Gilead training really helped us
to understand that things
wouldn’t always be easy.
And that when things weren’t easy,
we should never overreact to situations
but keep calm and trust in Jehovah.
I think one of the outstanding sections
of Gilead for me
was the section dealing with
the Gospels and Jesus Christ.
Jesus was always kind.
He was always reasonable
in his dealings with people.
And so in class, the emphasis was,
not on head knowledge,
but on how we can imitate Jesus Christ
in our dealings with others.
And I remember a couple of phrases:
People over productivity.
And the kind thing
is always the right thing to do.
These lessons are still with me
all these years later.
We were taught how to study.
And it helped us to study in a way
that would build a pool
or a foundation of principles
so that when we had a trial,
we would have somewhere to go
and dip into that pool of principles
that would apply to any situation
that we might face.
And it’s true
that at the time you go through it,
you’re taking in all the knowledge.
You don’t know when
and where you’re going to use it,
but it teaches you the method of:
Let’s store all this in the bank,
and then when I need it,
I know where I can go and pick it from.
One example that comes to mind
is a lecture we had
that highlighted Romans 15:3,
where it talked about
how “even the Christ did not please himself.”
So thinking about that lecture
makes me think of a situation
when we had been field missionaries
for a couple of years.
We were invited
to go into the traveling work.
So I was thinking to myself,
‘Can I really do this?’
But then I reflected back on that lecture
—Romans 15:3:
“The Christ [didn’t] please himself.”
It’s not about me.
It’s about doing Jehovah’s will.
It’s about the people you serve.
Reflecting on that helped me
to see myself
in that big picture and realize,
‘No, if Jesus could do that,
then this is what I have to do first
—I put the brothers and sisters first.’
And we thoroughly enjoyed being in that circuit.
I don’t even know why I was so worried.
Because at the end of three years,
we didn’t even want to leave.
The impact of Gilead
is not fully appreciated in the moment.
But as the years have gone by,
I do find myself reflecting on the lessons
that were taught during that class.
And I see how it’s shaped
the way I think and feel
all these years later.
So I would say, yeah,
it’s had a life- or personality-changing
effect on me.
When I think back of standing in that line,
I mean, it is very vivid
in my memory of how I felt.
And my stomach was definitely churning.
But these 28 years,
I have not regretted one single minute of it.
Being with the brothers and sisters,
serving in different forms of assignments,
I can definitely say
without one shadow of a doubt
that I still would not swap it for the world.
Well, we’ve enjoyed
a rich spiritual feast so far.
But there’s more to come.
What a blessing these graduates will be
to the brothers and sisters
in their assignments!
The second and third parts of the graduation
will be available on jw.org later this month.
We know you’re excited
to see the rest of the program.
To conclude this month’s broadcast,
let’s go to Tahiti.
It’s the main island of French Polynesia,
a territory of about 118 inhabited islands.
It’s a beautiful land marked by mountains,
waterfalls, and white sand atolls.
The surroundings teem with life.
Manta rays glide through the water
while the land produces
an abundance of beautiful flower species.
The beauty of this island
is found not only in its natural scenery
but also in the hospitable attitude
of the people.
Our brothers and sisters
of the Vaima Congregation make it a priority
to share the beauty of God’s Word.
Their territory extends from the city center
to the mountains and remote islands
of Apataki and Rikitea.
They witness to the local fishermen
at the beach
and to the international sailors
at its large harbors,
and their efforts have proven successful.
Currently, the congregation
is conducting 107 Bible studies.
And yes, 107 brothers and sisters
from the Vaima Congregation
send their warm greetings to you
wherever you are globally!
From the World Headquarters
of Jehovah’s Witnesses,
this is JW Broadcasting!